<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Eclipse Tractus-X Blog</title>
        <link>https://eclipse-tractusx.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Eclipse Tractus-X Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Eclipse Tractus-X Community Days]]></title>
            <link>https://eclipse-tractusx.github.io/blog/community-days</link>
            <guid>community-days</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Eclipse Tractus-X Community Days - Empowering the Catena-X Data Space]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="eclipse tractus x logo" src="/assets/images/Eclipse-TractusX-CommunityDays_Event2-751cfa514180f41744763b5ff3a4d58f.png" width="1880" height="940" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Dear Tractus-X-Community, dear All,
being interested in Catena-X and the open source reference implementations, KITs and open core products in the Tractus-X project or in general in the technology of data sovereign data exchange,</p><p><strong>We are pleased to announce the First Eclipse Tractus-X Community Days, which will take place on December 7th and 8th at ARENA2036 in Stuttgart.</strong></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="worth-being-there">Worth being there<a class="hash-link" href="#worth-being-there" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>At this networking and coding event at ARENA2036, we offer you the opportunity to come together live with the developer community and actively code with our Tractus-X IT tools (KITs) for the Eclipse Tractus-X project and exchange ideas with our technical experts. Gain deep insights into the Catena-X architecture and actively contribute your ideas to practical participation opportunities (use cases, KITs, services).</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-awaits-you">What awaits you<a class="hash-link" href="#what-awaits-you" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The agenda includes short keynote speeches with highly interesting technical insights, deep dives for a practical introduction to open-source programming topics and IT tools (our Open-Source Tractus-X KITs) and, above all, workshops in which you can become active and code yourself. You can bring your own challenges (please coordinate with us beforehand). At the evening event on the first day you can network, talk shop, code until late into the night - and of course just have fun. </p><div><div><img class="img_A5K3" src="/assets/images/Eclipse_CommunityDay1-d0a2de695511e4e5c434b4f537a96f4d.png"></div><div><img class="img_A5K3" src="/assets/images/Eclipse_CommunityDay2-d32798767472ffb18ae510d6ad0fb72b.png"></div></div><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="who-meets-here">Who meets here<a class="hash-link" href="#who-meets-here" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Developers who use Tractus-X or want to participate.</li><li>Service or solution providers who want to participate in the Catena-X ecosystem. </li><li>Data providers who want to provide data in the right format and with the right semantics.</li><li>Those responsible for the planning and development of products (product owners or product managers) who want to learn how projects are planned in open source.</li></ul><p>You belong to one of the above, then you are exactly right here. With the support of experts and in exchange with like-minded people, you can actively test the possibilities of Tractus-X and the Catena-X KITs. But of course, other technology-loving participants with an interest in sovereign data exchange are also welcomed.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-you-can-participate">How you can participate<a class="hash-link" href="#how-you-can-participate" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>If you would like to join, please register for free via Eventbrite:
<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/first-eclipse-tractus-x-community-days-tickets-721974885317?aff=oddtdtcreator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tractus-X Community Days registration</a>. The number of places is limited, so it is worth being quick!</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="contact">Contact<a class="hash-link" href="#contact" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>If you have any questions about the event, please contact <a href="mailto:heike.wohlfeld@arena2036.de." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">heike.wohlfeld@arena2036.de.</a> </p><p><strong>Get to know the developer community live and network with like-minded people - we look forward to your creativity and contributions!
Your Tractus-X Team</strong></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="presenters-of-the-event">Presenters of the event<a class="hash-link" href="#presenters-of-the-event" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>This is an Eclipse Tractus-X event, which takes place within the framework of the Catena-X Automotive Network consortium project (funding code: 13IK004*) and the Catena-X Automotive Network e.V.. ARENA2036 will host the event on its premises and contribute its data space activities (ARENA-X).</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>daniel.miehle@bmw.de (Daniel Miehle)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tractus-X 23.09 available now]]></title>
            <link>https://eclipse-tractusx.github.io/blog/new-release-23.09</link>
            <guid>new-release-23.09</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Release Tractus-X 23.09 announcement]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="eclipse tractus x logo" src="/assets/images/release_23.09-b51a70711e3c20313f60838f9fa90dfe.png" width="660" height="426" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We are pleased to announce the <a href="https://github.com/eclipse-tractusx/tractus-x-release/releases/tag/23.09" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tractus-X Release 23.09!</a> This release brings important improvements to our Catena-X operating system and KITs in terms of robustness, data sovereignty, compliance, and overall user experience for all data space participants.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="catena-x-operating-system-cxos">Catena-X Operating System (cxOS):<a class="hash-link" href="#catena-x-operating-system-cxos" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>We are introducing a decentralized registry for digital twins and a managed identity wallet based on self-sovereign identities to <strong>maximize sovereignty</strong> of all data space participants. In addition, we offer the first ever integration with a Gaia-X Digital Clearing House (GXDCH) to foster <strong>trust</strong> and <strong>data space interoperability</strong>.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="eclipse tractus x logo" src="/assets/images/release_23.09_cx_os-6dd2a63e70448fe222bfeba2bf1467de.png" width="1717" height="256" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="use-cases--value-creation">Use Cases &amp; Value Creation:<a class="hash-link" href="#use-cases--value-creation" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>With <strong>six new KITs</strong>, we are introducing exiting new offerings and standards for our solution providers and data providers to <strong>build a multi-vendor ecosystem</strong> of applications and services.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="data-space-governance">Data Space Governance:<a class="hash-link" href="#data-space-governance" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The <a href="https://catena-x.net/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Catena-X Automotive Network e.V.</a> will introduce significant advancements in the governance framework for data space operations by providing the <strong>flight level model</strong> and new <strong>use case policies</strong> by end of the of the month.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>daniel.miehle@bmw.de (Daniel Miehle)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tractus-X 3.1 available now]]></title>
            <link>https://eclipse-tractusx.github.io/blog/new-release-3-1-0</link>
            <guid>new-release-3-1-0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Release Tractus-X 3.1.0 announcement]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the release of <a href="https://eclipse-tractusx.github.io/CHANGELOG/#310---2023-05-17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tractus-X 3.1!</a> This release brings important improvements to the robustness, quality, and overall user experience of the Catena-X data space. In addition, we introduce exciting new offerings for our solution providers such as the Traceability KIT and the Country Risk Service.</p><p>With version 3.1, the Catena-X Association also introduces significant advancements in data sovereignty by providing the first version of the <a href="https://catena-x.net/en/catena-x-introduce-implement/governance-framework-for-data-space-operations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Governance Framework</a> as well as <a href="https://catena-x.net/fileadmin/user_upload/04_Einfuehren_und_umsetzen/Framework_Use_Case_Traceability/Catena-X_Use_Case_Policies_Trace_3.0_EN.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Policies for our use case Traceability</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>daniel.miehle@bmw.de (Daniel Miehle)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eclipse Tractus-X Developer Portal is LIVE!]]></title>
            <link>https://eclipse-tractusx.github.io/blog/portal-is-live</link>
            <guid>portal-is-live</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Official launch announcement]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="eclipse tractus x logo" src="/assets/images/logo-blog-e7eb77d0248c3698817726c33a196d8b.png" width="660" height="426" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We are thrilled to announce the launch of the Developer Portal for the Eclipse Tractus-X project! This portal is designed to provide developers with an easy way to access all of our resources and documentation.</p><p>With this new portal, we aim to make it easier than ever before for developers around the world to get started building amazing projects on top of the Catena-X network. We have included our initial KITs and developer guides that will help you develop your solution. Step by step we will also provide a comprehensive overview of useful reference material.</p><p>The best part? All these resources are free and open-source! So what’s stopping you from taking advantage right now? Let’s get coding together and build something amazing with Tractus-X today!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>daniel.miehle@bmw.de (Daniel Miehle)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>